《加勒比海盗：黑珍珠号的诅咒》
∮ 让我们痛饮吧 兄弟们 ∮
∮ Drink up, me hearties, yo ho ∮
∮ 烧杀抢掠是我们的乐趣 ∮
∮ We kidnap and ravage and don't give a hoot ∮
∮ 让我们痛饮吧 兄弟们 ∮
∮ Drink up, me hearties, yo ho ∮
∮ 哟呼 哟呼 ∮
∮ Yo ho, yo ho ∮
∮ 我是一个海盗 ∮
∮ A pirate's life for me ∮
∮ 所以我勒索 我偷窃 我毫不在乎 ∮
∮ We extort, we pilfer, we filch and sack ∮
∮ 干杯吧 朋友 ∮
∮ Drink up ∮
不要唱了 小姐
Quiet, missy.
这儿常有海盗出没
Cursed pirates sail these waters.
你也不想引他们来吧
You don't want to bring them.
够了 吉布斯
Mr. Gibbs, that will do.
她在唱海盗的歌呢
She was singing about pirates.
在这不寻常的浓雾里
It's bad luck to be singing about pirates
唱着海盗的歌会给我们带来厄运的
with us mired in this unnatural fog.
记住我的话吧
Mark my words.
我已经记住了
Consider them marked.
你去干你的活吧
On your way.
是的 上尉
Aye, Lieutenant.
带女人上船总会带来厄运
It's bad luck to have a woman on board, too.
即使是这么小的
Even a miniature one.
我觉得如果能遇上海盗的话 也会是一件值得兴奋的事
I think it'd be rather exciting to meet a pirate.
再想想吧 斯旺小姐
Think again, Miss Swann.
他们是卑鄙且放荡的人
Vile and dissolute creatures, the lot of them.
如果让我看到他们的旗子
I intend that any man who sails under a pirate flag
或是他们的衣服的话 我会毫不犹豫地给他们应有的惩罚
or wears a pirate brand gets what he deserves.
让他们在绞刑架上就这么一落一停
A short drop and a sudden stop.
诺灵顿上尉 我对此表示感激
Lieutenant Norrington, I appreciate your fervor,
不过我担心这会对我女儿产生
but I'm concerned about the effect
不好的影响
this subject will have upon my daughter.
对不起 斯旺市长
My apologies, Governor Swann.
其实我觉得这都挺有趣的
Actually, I find it all fascinating.
这就是我所担心的
Yes. That's what concerns me.
看! 那儿有个男孩在水面上漂着!
Look! A boy! There's a boy in the water!
有人落水了
Man overboard!
把绳子放下去 拿钩子来
Man the ropes. Fetch a hook.
把他拉上来
Haul him aboard.
他还有呼吸
He's still breathing.
我的天哪!
Mary, Mother of God.
发生什么事了?
What happened here?
摧毁它需要有一定量的武器
It's the powder magazine.
商船一般都有很好的武装
Merchant vessels run heavily armed.
他们可真客气
A lot of good it did them.
我只是说出每个人所想的
Everyone's thinking it. I'm just saying it.
是海盗!
Pirates.
这不可能 一般来说这只是一个意外事故
There's no proof of that. It's probably an accident.
向船长预警
Rouse the captain immediately.
准备全速航行 起航!
Heave to and take in sail. Launch the boats.
伊丽莎白 我希望你陪着那男孩
Elizabeth, I want you to accompany the boy.
你负责照料他
He'll be in your charge.
好好做
Take care of him.
没事的
It's okay.
我叫伊丽莎白 斯旺
My name's Elizabeth Swann.
威尔 特纳
Will Turner.
我会照顾你的
I'm watching over you, Will.
你是个海盗!
You're a pirate.
他说什么了吗?
Has he said anything?
我只知道他叫威尔 特纳
His name's William Turner. That's all I found out.
把他带到船舱去
Take him below.
伊丽莎白?
Elizabeth?
你没事吧?
Are you all right?
你穿好衣服了吗?
Are you decent?
是的
Yes.
好了
现在还在睡?
Still abed at this hour?
美好的一天!
Oh, it's a beautiful day.
我有一个礼物要送你
I have a gift for you.
太漂亮了
Oh, it's beautiful.
不是吗?
lsn't it?
有什么特别的理由吗?
May I inquire as to the occasion?
难道一个父亲送给女儿礼物还要什么理由吗?
Does a father need an occasion to dote upon his daughter?
去
Go on.
事实上...
Actually, l...
我希望你能在今天的典礼上穿着它
I hoped you might wear it for the ceremony today.
典礼?
The ceremony?
诺灵顿上校的升职典礼
Captain Norrington's promotion ceremony.
我就知道
I knew it.
他将成为诺灵顿准将
Commodore Norrington, as he's about to become.
一个不错的绅士 你觉得呢?
A fine gentleman, don't you think?
他喜欢你
He fancies you, you know.
伊丽莎白? 感觉怎么样?
Elizabeth? How's it coming?
很难说
It's difficult to say.
这是伦敦最流行的款式
I'm told it's the latest fashion in London.
那么伦敦的女人一定不用呼吸
Well, women in London must've learnt not to breathe.
老爷 你有一个客人
Milord, you have a visitor.
特纳先生
Mr. Turner.
很高兴能再见到你
Good to see you again.
早上好 先生
Good day, sir.
我拿来了你要的东西
I have your order.
哦
Well.
刀刃是钢质的
The blade is folded steel.
在刀柄处镶有金子
That's gold filigree laid into the handle.
如果我可以的话
If I may.
完美的平衡
Perfectly balanced.
柄脚和刀刃基本同宽
The tang is nearly the full width of the blade.
很好 太美妙了!
lmpressive. Very impressive.
啊
Now, now.
诺灵顿准将一定会很满意的
Commodore Norrington is going to be very pleased with this.
向你的师傅表达我对他的谢意
Do pass my compliments on to your master.
我会的
I shall.
一个工匠总希望自己的作品 能被人喜欢
A craftsman is always pleased to hear his work is appreciated.
伊丽莎白 你看起来好美
Elizabeth, you look absolutely stunning.
威尔
Will.
能见到你实在是太好了
It's so good to see you.
我昨晚梦见你了
I had a dream about you last night.
我?
About me?
你觉得这样合适吗?
Yes, is that entirely proper for you ...
你记得我们相遇的那天吗?
About the day we met. Do you remember?
我怎么会忘记呢 斯旺小姐
How could I forget, Miss Swann?
我要跟你说多少次 叫我伊丽莎白
How many times must I ask you to call me Elizabeth?
最起码再多一次 斯旺小姐
At least once more, Miss Swann, as always.
你瞧
There. See?
这孩子可懂礼貌多了
At least the boy has a sense of propriety.
我们得走了
We really must be going. There you are.
再见 特纳先生
Good day, Mr. Turner.
过来
Come along.
再见
Good day.
伊丽莎白
Elizabeth.
嘿
What ... hey.
你给我站住
Hold up, there, you.
你要缴付一先令 才能让你的船停靠
It's a shilling to tie up your boat at the dock.
而且你得告诉我你的名字
And I shall need to know your name.
我给你三先令
What do you say to three shillings,
我们不要再讲名字的问题了
and we forget the name?
欢迎来到皇家港 史密斯先生
Welcome to Port Royal, Mr. Smith.
向前两步走!
Two paces march!
向后转!
Right about-face!
拿起武器!
Present arms!
一般民众不能进入这个码头
This dock is off limits to civilians.
对不起 我不知道
I'm terribly sorry. I didn't know.
如果我看到的话会告诉你们的
If I see one, I shall inform you immediately.
在那儿似乎有不少好玩的东西
There's some sort of high-toned and fancy to-do up at the fort.
为什么像你们这样出色的士兵
How could it be two upstanding gentlemen such as yourselves
没有权力进去观赏呢?
did not merit an invitation?
因为需要有人来确保 一般民众不进入那码头
Someone has to make sure this dock stays off limits.
这是一个高尚的目标
It's a fine goal, to be sure.
不过我觉得那边的船
But it seems to me that a ship like that
让这里的一艘相形见绌了
makes this one here a bit superfluous, really.
无畏号是海上的霸主没错
The Dauntless is the power in these waters, true.
但以速度上来讲 没有船能比过拦截号
But there's no ship as can match the Interceptor for speed.
我听说过一艘更快的
I've heard of one.
他几乎是无法追上的
It's supposed to be very fast. Nigh uncatchable.
黑珍珠
The Black Pearl,
没有实际存在的船 能比得上拦截号
Well, there's no real ship as can match the Interceptor,
黑珍珠是实际存在的
Black Pearl is a real ship.
不 它不是
No. No, it's not.
它是的 我曾经看到过
Yes, it is. I've seen it.
你看到过?
You've seen it?
是的
Yes.
你没看过
You haven't seen it.
我看过
Yes, I have.
你看过黑帆的船
You've seen a ship with black sails
被一群混蛋水手和邪恶船长驾驶
that's crewed by the damned and captained by a man so evil
连地狱都不欢迎他们
that Hell itself spat him back out?
不
No.
我确实看过黑帆的船
But I have seen a ship with black sails.
哦
Oh.
没有其他的船
No ship that's not crewed by the damned
被一群混蛋水手和邪恶船长驾驶的
and captained by a man so evil that Hell spat him out
会有黑色的帆
could possibly have black sails, therefore couldn't be
所以除了黑珍珠不可能有别的
any other ship than the Black Pearl,
这是你想说的吗?
Is that what you're saying?
不
No.
就像我说的
Like I said, there's no real ship
没有实际存在的船赶得上拦截号
as can match the Interceptor,
嘿!
Hey!
你!
You!
走开!
Get away from there!
你不能来这儿
You don't have permission to be there.
对不起 这船太美了
I'm sorry. It's such a pretty boat.
轮船
Ship.
你叫什么名字?
What's your name?
史密斯 如果你愿意的话 史密西
Smith. Or Smithy, if you like.
你来皇家港的目的是什么?
What's your purpose in Port Royal, Mr. Smith?
是的 不准说谎
Yeah. And no lies.
我承认
Well, then, I confess.
我想要霸占一艘船
It is my intention to commandeer one of these ships,
在托图加招一些水手烧杀抢掠
pick up a crew in Tortuga, raid, pillage, plunder,
再把那些告密者杀了
and otherwise pilfer my weaselly black guts out.
- 我说过不许说谎 - 我觉得他说的是实话
- I said no lies. - I think he's telling the truth.
如果这是实话的话 他就不会告诉我们
If he were telling the truth, he wouldn't have told us.
你就连是真话也不愿相信
Unless you wouldn't believe the truth even if he told you.
你可以过来一下吗?
May I have a moment?
你看起来很漂亮 伊丽莎白
You look lovely, Elizabeth.
我对我的直接表示抱歉 但我一定要说出我的心声
I apologize if I seem forward, but I must speak my mind.
这次的晋升
This promotion throws into sharp relief
使我如释重负
that which I have not yet achieved.
我期望娶一个好女人
A marriage to a fine woman.
而你就是那个好女人 伊丽莎白
You have become a fine woman, Elizabeth.
我不能呼吸了
I can't breathe.
我也很紧张
Yes, I'm a bit nervous myself.
然后我被他们选为头领
And then they made me their chief.
伊丽莎白?
Elizabeth?
伊丽莎白!
Elizabeth!
我的天哪
My God.
那些岩石!
The rocks!
她没掉在上面已经是奇迹了
Sir, it's a miracle she missed them.
- 你会去救她吗? - 我不会游泳
- Will you be saving her? - I can't swim.
你是国王舰队的荣耀
Pride of the King's Navy, you are.
不要丢了
Do not lose these.
这是什么?
What was that?
让开!
Make way!
她在这儿!
I got her!
她没有呼吸了!
She's not breathing!
走开!
Move!
我可想不到会是这个
I never would've thought of that.
很明显你没去过新加坡
Clearly you've never been to Singapore.
你从哪里得到的?
Where did you get that?
站起来
On your feet.
伊丽莎白
Elizabeth!
你没事吧?
Are you all right?
我没事
Yes, I'm fine.
开枪
Shoot him.
- 爸爸 - 怎么了?
- Father. - What?
准将 难道你要杀了我的救命恩人吗?
Commodore, do you really intend to kill my rescuer?
我相信一次感谢已足够了
I believe thanks are in order.
在东印度公司见过面 不是吗 海盗?
Had a brush with the East lndia Trading Company, did we, pirate?
把他绑起来
Hang him.
把枪对准他 吉雷特 拿些铁链来
Keep your guns on him, men. Gillette, fetch some irons.
哦
Well, well.
杰克 斯派洛 是吧?
Jack Sparrow, isn't it?
杰克 斯派洛船长 更确切一些
Captain Jack Sparrow, if you please, sir.
船长 那么你的船呢?
Well, I don't see your ship, Captain.
我正在寻找
I'm in the market, as it were.
他说他要抢一艘
He said he'd come to commandeer one.
我早说过他说的是实话 这些东西是他的 长官
Told you he was telling the truth. These are his, sir.
没有子弹
No additional shot nor powder.
不会指北的指南针
A compass that doesn't point North.
我还以为这也是木头做的呢!
And I half expected it to be made of wood.
你毫无疑问是我见过最差劲的海盗
You are without doubt the worst pirate I've ever heard of.
但你一定听说过我
But you have heard of me.
准将 我要抗议
Commodore, I really must protest.
小心点上尉
Carefully, Lieutenant.
不管他是不是海盗 它救过我的命
Pirate or not, this man saved my life.
一次善行掩盖不了他以前的恶迹
One good deed is not enough to redeem a man
看起来他是罪无可恕了
Though it seems enough to condemn him.
没错
lndeed.
终于
Finally.
不
No.
不要开枪!
No! Don't shoot!
我知道你会帮我的
I knew you'd warm up to me.
诺灵顿准将 我的东西
Commodore Norrington, my effects, please.
还有帽子
And my hat.
准将
Commodore.
- 你叫伊丽莎白? - 是斯旺小姐
- lt is Elizabeth, isn't it? - It's Miss Swann.
帮我穿上它 斯旺小姐
Miss Swann, if you'd be so kind.
快点 亲爱的 时间不多了
Come, come, dear. We don't have all day.
如果你可以的话
Now if you'll be very kind.
小心点 宝贝
Easy on the goods, darling.
你这个卑鄙小人
You're despicable.
好过去送死
Sticks and stones, love.
我救你一命你还我一命 大家扯平
I saved your life. You save mine. We're square.
先生们 女士们 你们将永远记住这一天
Gentlemen, milady, you will always remember this
因为你们差点就抓住了杰克 斯派洛
as the day that you almost caught Captain Jack Sparrow.
哇!
Whoa!
你们现在可以开枪了
Now will you shoot him?
开枪!
Open fire!
嘿!
Hey!
追!
On his heels!
我掩护你!
Take cover, man!
吉雷特 斯派洛先生和 绞刑架有一个约会
Gillette, Mr. Sparrow has a dawn appointment with the gallows.
我不希望他迟到了
I would hate for him to miss it.
搜楼上!
Search upstairs!
仔细找!
Look lively, men!
哇!
Whoa!
没动过
Right where I left you.
被人动过了
Not where I left you.
你是他们在找的人
You're the one they're hunting.
海盗
The pirate.
你看起来很面熟 我曾经威胁过你吗?
You seem familiar. Have I threatened you before?
我只是不愿和海盗搭上关系
I make a point of avoiding familiarity with pirates.
那对玷污你的记录感到抱歉
It would be a shame to put a mark on your record.
如果你允许的话
So if you'll excuse me.
你觉得这样做理智吗?
Do you think this wise, boy?
和一个海盗比剑
Crossing blades with a pirate?
你曾试图伤害斯旺小姐
You threatened Miss Swann.
一点点而已
Only a little.
既然你执意要如此 我就陪你玩玩 剑术还不赖
You know what you're doing. I'll give you that. Excellent form.
那么脚步呢?
But how's your footwork?
如果我走这边
If I step here.
很好
Very good.
我再走一步
And now I step again.
不错
Ta.
这把戏看起来不错
That is a wonderful trick.
只是你阻挡了我逃跑
Except, once again, you are between me and my way out.
而且你现在已经没有武器了
And now you have no weapon.
这些剑是谁造的?
Who makes all these?
我
I do.
而且我每天都练三个小时
And I practice with them three hours a day.
朋友 你得为你自己找个女孩
You need to find yourself a girl, mate.
又或者你每天练三小时的原因
Or perhaps the reason you practice three hours a day
是你已经找到了一个
is that you found one
只不过还没得到她
and are otherwise incapable of wooing said strumpet.
你不会是太监吧?
You're not a eunuch, are you?
我每天练三小时 是为了当我遇见一个海盗的时候
I practice three hours a day so when I meet a pirate,
我能亲手杀了他!
I can kill it!
你耍手段
You cheated.
我是海盗
Pirate.
走开
Move away.
不
No.
- 请走开 - 不
- Please move. - No.
我不可以坐视你离开
I cannot just step aside and let you escape.
这一枪本不是为你准备的
This shot is not meant for you.
他在这儿!
There he is! Over here!
做得很好 布朗先生
Excellent work, Mr. Brown.
你帮助我们抓到了一个逃犯
You've assisted in the capture of a fugitive.
我只是尽我的公民义务而已 长官
Just doing my civic duty, sir.
我相信你一定会记住
I trust you will remember this is the day
这一天杰克 斯派洛几乎逃跑了
Captain Jack Sparrow almost escaped.
把他带走
Take him away.
- 闻到了吗? - 快过来
- Can you smell it? - Come here.
- 这儿有肉骨头 - 过来
- It's marrowbone. - Come here.
- 看这美味的骨头 - 来
- Want a juicy bone? - Come here.
- 乖 过来 - 快过来
- Come here, boy! - Come on.
你们这样是没用的 那狗绝对不会过来的
You can keep doing that forever. The dog is never going to move.
哦 对不起
Oh, excuse us
因为我们还不想上绞刑架
if we haven't resigned ourself to the gallows just yet.
小姐
There you go, miss.
今天的经历一定让你受惊了
It was a difficult day for you, I'm sure.
我之前就料到诺灵顿准将会向我求婚
I suspected Commodore Norrington would propose.
但我还是没有什么准备
I must admit, I wasn't prepared for it.
我是说你被那个海盗挟持 听起来怪可怕的
I meant you being threatened by that pirate. Sounds terrifying.
哦
Oh.
那是怪可怕的
Yes, it was terrifying.
诺灵顿准将终于向你求婚了 真令人羡慕
But the commodore proposed. Fancy that.
恕我直言 你们可真是郎才女貌
Now, that's a smart match, miss, if it's not too bold to say.
我们确实是
It is a smart match.
他是个好男人
He's a fine man.
一个任何女人都想要嫁的好男人
He's what any woman should dream of marrying.
不过那个威尔 特纳也不错
Well, that Will Turner. He's a fine man, too.
我想这有点过分了
That is too bold.
对不起 小姐 我想我还是走了
Well, begging your pardon, miss. It was not my place.
我的女儿给你答复了吗?
Has my daughter given you an answer yet?
她还没
No, she hasn't.
今天对她来说可不容易
Well, she has had a very trying day.
坏天气 你觉得呢?
Ghastly weather, don't you think?
非常阴冷
Bleak. Very bleak.
那是什么?
What's that?
炮弹!
Cannon fire!
还击!
Return fire!
- 我知道是谁 - 全副武装!
- I know those guns. - Men to arms!
是珍珠
It's the Pearl,
黑珍珠?
The Black Pearl?
我听过它的故事
I've heard stories.
它到处抢掠已有十多年了
She's been preying on ships and settlements for near 10 years.
从来没有一个生还者
Never leaves any survivors.
没有生还者?
No survivors?
那这些故事是从哪儿来的?
Then where do the stories come from, I wonder?
冲啊!
Coming through!
啊!
Aaah!
看清那些亮点!
Sight the muzzle flash!
瞄准亮点!
Aim for the flashes!
我要对整艘船进行炮轰
I need a full strike, fore and aft.
施蒂芬斯 再多点弹药
Mr. Stephens, more cartridges!
去我的办公室躲起来 市长
Governor, barricade yourself in my office.
这是命令!
That's an order.
不要!
Don't!
朋友 你好
Hello, chum.
在上面
Up there.
斯旺小姐 他们来绑架你
Miss Swann, they've come to kidnap you!
什么?
What?
因为你是市长的女儿!
You're the governor's daughter.
在这儿!
In here!
他们没有看到你
Listen. They haven't seen you.
快跑去堡垒那边
The first chance you get, run to the fort.
找到你了
Gotcha.
不要! 好烫啊!
No! No! No! It's hot!
你敢烧我!
You burned me!
快!
Come on!
不!
No!
乖孩子 我知道你在这儿
We know you're here, poppet.
乖孩子
Poppet.
出来吧 我们不会伤害你的
Come out and we promise we won't hurt you.
恩?
Eh?
我们会找到你的 乖孩子
We will find you, poppet.
是你手里的东西召唤我们来的
You've got something of ours, and it calls to us.
那金子在召唤我们
The gold calls to us.
金子
Gold.
你好 乖孩子
Hello, poppet.
帕雷
Parley.
啊?
What?
帕雷
Parley.
我请求帕雷的权利
I invoke the right of parley.
根据摩根和巴塞洛缪制定的海盗法典
According to the Code of the Brethren set down by the pirates Morgan and Bartholomew,
你必须带我去见你们的船长
you have to take me to your captain.
我听说过法典
I know the Code.
如果俘虏要求帕雷的话
If an adversary demands parley,
我们不能伤害她直至仪式结束
you can do them no harm until the parley is complete.
让法典见鬼去吧
To blazes with the Code.
她想要见船长
She wants to be taken to the captain.
所以任何人都不可以阻挠
And she'll go without a fuss.
我们必须遵照法典行事
We must honor the Code.
说再见吧
Say goodbye.
再见
Goodbye.
- 威尔! - 快!
- Will! - Come on!
伊丽莎白
Elizabeth.
走开人渣!
Out of my way, scum!
对不起了朋友
My sympathies, friend.
看来你不怎么走运
You've no manner of luck at all.
狗儿 过来
Come on, doggy.
现在只有我们俩了
It's just you and me now.
只有你和我了 快过来
It's you and old Jack. Come on.
来 听话
Come on. That's a boy.
乖孩子 尝尝这骨头
Good boy. Come get the bone.
这才是个好孩子 来
That's a good boy. Come on.
再近一点
A bit closer. A bit closer.
对了 乖狗儿
That's it. That's it, doggy.
快 你这污秽的杂种
Come on, you filthy, slimy, mangy cur.
不要
Don't do that.
不不不! 我不是这个意思!
No, no! I didn't mean it!
我不是
I didn't.
这里不是军械库
This ain't the armory.
看看这是谁 提格
Well, well, well. Look what we have here, Twigg.
杰克 斯派洛船长
Captain Jack Sparrow.
我最后一次见你
Last time I saw you,
你一个人在一个要命的荒岛上
you were all alone on a godforsaken island,
在我的视野中慢慢消失
shrinking into the distance.
看来你的厄运还没有结束
His fortunes aren't improved much.
顾好你们自己吧 先生们
Worry about your own fortunes, gentlemen.
地狱的最底层 是为你们这些叛徒准备的
The deepest circle of hell is reserved for betrayers and mutineers.
是那咒语
So there is a curse.
很有趣
That's interesting.
你什么也不知道
You know nothing of hell.
太有趣了
That's very interesting.
我没料到我们会有俘虏
I didn't know we was taking on captives.
她要求行使帕雷的权利 所以我们带她来见巴伯萨船长
She's invoked the right of parley with Captain Barbossa.
- 我来这儿是... - 让你开口的时候你再开口
- I'm here to ... - You'll speak when spoken to.
我不希望再看到
And ye will not lay a hand
那些被帕雷保护着的人受到威胁
on those under the protection of parley.
是的 船长
Aye, sir.
我对此表示抱歉 小姐
My apologies, miss.
巴伯萨船长 我是来谈判的
Captain Barbossa, I am here to negotiate
我希望你们停止攻击皇家港
the cessation of hostilities against Port Royal.
好冗长的句子
There were a lot of long words in there.
我们只不过是一些出身低微的海盗
We're naught but humble pirates.
简单点吧
What is it that you want?
我希望你们离开 并且永远不要回来
I want you to leave and never come back.
我倾向于拒绝你的要求
I'm disinclined to acquiesce to your request.
也就是说"不"
Means "no."
很好
Very well.
那么我就扔了它
I'll drop it.
我好紧张阿
Me holds are bursting with swag.
你认为这闪闪发光的东西对我们很重要吗?
That bit of shine matters to us?
为什么?
Why?
这是你们要找的 我认得这艘船
It's what you've been searching for. I recognize this ship.
我在八年前见过它
I saw it eight years ago on the crossing from England.
是吗?
Did you, now?
那好
Fine.
我想既然它没什么意义的话
I suppose if it is worthless,
我也没有理由再留着它了
there's no point in me keeping it.
你叫什么名字 小姐?
You have a name, missy?
伊丽莎白 特纳
Elizabeth Turner.
我是市长家的一个女仆
I'm a maid in the governor's household.
特纳小姐
Miss Turner.
系带王
Bootstrap.
一个女仆怎会有如此珍贵的东西?
How does a maid own a trinket such as that?
家族继承的
Family heirloom, perhaps?
这不是偷的 如果你的意思的话
I didn't steal it, if that's what you mean.
很好 把它给我
Very well. Hand it over.
我们会离开你的城市永远不再回来
We'll put your town to our rudder and ne'er return.
我们的协议呢?
Our bargain?
停止开火
Still the guns and stow them.
等一下! 你得把我送上岸
Wait! You have to take me to shore!
根据法典的规定…
According to the Code ...
第一 我们的协议并不包括把你送上岸
First, your return to shore was not part of our agreement.
所以我没有这个义务
So I must do nothing.
第二 你必须是一个海盗 法典才会对你生效
You must be a pirate for the Pirate's Code to apply,
可惜你不是
and you're not.
第三 法典只不过是一些指导
Thirdly, the Code is more what you'd call guidelines
它并不是必须遵守的规定
than actual rules.
特纳小姐 欢迎来到黑珍珠
Welcome aboard the Black Pearl, Miss Turner.
他们抢走了她 他们把伊丽莎白抢走了
They've taken her. They've taken Elizabeth.
莫托先生 把这个人带走
Mr. Murtogg, remove this man.
我们要抓住他们 我们一定要救她!
We have to hunt them down. We must save her.
你觉得我们该怎么做?
And where do you propose we start?
如果你有有关我女儿的情报
If you have information concerning my daughter,
请你告诉我
please share it.
那个杰克 斯派洛提起过黑珍珠
That Jack Sparrow. He talked about the Black Pearl,
只是提起而已
Mentioned it is more what he did.
问他试试看 他也许会带我们去
Ask him where it is. He could lead us to it.
不 那些攻击我们的海盗
No. The pirates who invaded this fort
并没有救走他 所以他们不可能是一伙的
left Sparrow locked in his cell, ergo they are not his allies.
我们会试着去找到他们可能的航线
We will establish their most likely course.
这不够!
That's not good enough!
特纳先生 你不是一个军人
Mr. Turner, you are not a military man.
不是一个水手
You are not a sailor.
你只不过是一个铁匠
You are a blacksmith.
而且这不是意气用事的时候
And this is not the moment for rash actions.
不要以为你是唯一一个
Do not make the mistake of thinking
担心伊丽莎白的人
you are the only man here who cares for Elizabeth.
斯派洛
You. Sparrow.
你对那艘黑珍珠很熟吧
You are familiar with that ship. The Black Pearl,
我听说过
I've heard of it.
它会在哪里停靠?
Where does it make berth?
你听说过
Have you not heard the stories?
巴伯萨船长和他那群走狗的故事吗?
Captain Barbossa and his crew of miscreants
他们来自死亡之岛
sail from the dreaded lsla de Muerta.
一个除了去过那儿
It's an island that cannot be found,
没有其他人能够找得到的小岛
except by those who already know where it is.
那艘船是存在的
The ship's real enough.
所以它停靠的地方也一定存在
lts anchorage must be a real place.
在哪儿?
Where is it?
你为什么问我?
Why ask me?
因为你是海盗
Because you're a pirate.
那么你自己也想成为海盗?
And you want to turn pirate yourself, is that it?
永远不会
Never.
他们带走了斯旺小姐
They took Miss Swann.
哦 你终于找到了你的女孩
Oh, so it is that you found a girl.
我明白了 不过你要英雄救美的话
I see. Well, if you're intending to brave all,
要获得她的心
hasten to her rescue, and so win fair lady's heart,
你必须一个人去做 朋友
you'll have to do it alone, mate.
我看不出这对我会有任何好处
I see no profit in it for me.
我能把你救出来
I can get you out of here.
怎么救? 已经没有钥匙了
How's that? They key's run off.
这牢房是我造的
I helped build these cells.
这些是半固定的铁链
These are half-pin barrel hinges.
利用杠杆原理和一些巧力
With the right leverage and the proper application of strength.
就能轻松地把它抬起来
The door will lift free.
你叫什么名字?
What's your name?
威尔 特纳
Will Turner.
那是威廉的缩写是吧?
That would be short for William, I imagine.
好名字
Good, strong name.
毫无疑问是随你父亲的
No doubt named for your father.
没错
Yes.
恩
Uh-huh.
特纳先生 我改变了我的决定
Well, Mr. Turner, I've changed me mind.
如果你能把我救出去的话
If you spring me from this cell, I swear on pain of death
我会不顾一切把你带到黑珍珠上
I shall take you to the Black Pearl
去见你的心肝宝贝
and your bonny lass.
那么我们就有了约定?
Do we have an accord?
同意
Agreed.
把我弄出去
Get me out.
快一点 有人会听见的
Hurry. Someone will have heard that.
不能忘了我的东西
Not without my effects.
我们要去偷船?
We're going to steal the ship?
那条?
That ship?
霸占
Commandeer.
我们要去抢那艘船
We're going to commandeer that ship.
这是我们的行话
Nautical term.
我还有一个问题
One question about your business.
否则我们也没有出发的必要
Or there's no use going.
你为了那个女孩
This girl.
可以牺牲到怎样的程度?
How far are you willing to go to save her?
我可以为她去死
I'd die for her.
很好
Oh, good.
那就没什么疑问了
No worries, then.
疯狂和伟大之间只有一线之隔
This is either madness or brilliance.
他们往往是相伴而行的
It's remarkable how often those two traits coincide.
大家不要惊慌! 我们已经控制了这条船
Everyone stay calm! We are taking over the ship.
不要动!
Aye! Avast!
两个人是驾驭不了这条船的
This ship cannot be crewed by two men.
你永远也开不出这个码头
You'll never make it out of the bay.
小子 我是斯派洛船长
Son, I'm Captain Jack Sparrow.
懂了吗?
Savvy?
准将
Commodore.
长官 他们抢走了无畏号
Sir, they've taken the Dauntless!
准将!
Commodore!
他们把船抢走了!
They've taken the ship!
斯派洛和特纳把无畏号抢走了!
Sparrow and Turner have taken the Dauntless!
特纳 你太鲁莽了
Rash, Turner. Too rash.
毫无疑问他是我见过的最难缠的海盗
That is without doubt the worst pirate I have ever seen.
他们来了
Here they come.
转舵! 转舵!
Bring her around! Bring her around!
全面搜查这艘船
Search every cabin, every hull, down to the bilges.
水手们 快回去拦截号
Sailors, back to the Interceptor,
快!
Now!
谢谢你 准将
Thank you, Commodore, for getting us ready to make way.
你为我们省了不少力气
We'd have had a hard time of it by ourselves.
扬帆全速航行
Set topsails and clear up this mess.
在有风的情况下我们根本追不上它
With the wind, we won't catch them.
我并不想追上它 只要让它进入我们的射程范围之内
I don't need to. Get them in range of the long nines.
准备!
Hands, come about!
伸出炮头!
Run out the guns!
我们要击毁自己的船 长官?
We are to fire on our own ship, sir?
我宁愿看到它沉睡在海底
I'd rather see her at the bottom of the ocean
也不能让他落入海盗的手中
than in the hands of a pirate.
准将 他把舵给定死了
Commodore, he's disabled the rudder chain, sir.
弃船!
Abandon ship!
他是我见过最厉害的海盗
That's got to be the best pirate I've ever seen.
看来是了
So it would seem.
在我还是个小孩的时候
WlLL: When I was a lad living in England,
我妈一个人把我拉扯大
my mother raised me by herself.
她死了之后 我就来这儿找我爸
After she died, I came out here, looking for my father.
是吗?
Is that so?
我的爸爸 威尔 特纳
My father, Will Turner.
你是听了他的名字之后才决定帮我的
It was only after you learnt my name you agreed to help.
因为这也是我所希望的 所以我也没有深究
Since that's what I wanted, I didn't press the matter.
我不是傻子 杰克
I'm not a simpleton, Jack.
你认识我的父亲
You knew my father.
对 我认识他
I knew him.
也许是少数几个 知道他叫威廉特纳的人
Probably one of the few who knew him as William Turner.
大部分人都叫他系带王
Everyone else called him Bootstrap or Bootstrap Bill.
系带王?
Bootstrap?
一个好人 一个好海盗
Good man. Good pirate.
我发誓 你简直和他长得一模一样
I swear, you look just like him.
这不是真的
It's not true.
他是个跑货运的水手
He was a merchant sailor.
一个可敬守法的人
A respectable man who obeyed the law.
他是个凶残的海盗 一个恶棍
He was a bloody pirate. A scallywag.
我父亲不是海盗
My father was not a pirate.
放下它 孩子 不值得再被痛扁
Put it away, son. It's not worth you getting beat again.
你从来不按规则格斗
You ignored the rules of engagement.
不然我早杀了你了
In a fair fight, I'd kill you.
我没有必要按规矩交战 不是吗?
Then that's not much incentive for me to fight fair.
只要你还吊在那里 就听好了
Now, as long as you're just hanging there, pay attention.
真正唯一的规则是:
The only rules that really matter are these.
人可以做什么 人无法做什么
What a man can do and what a man can't do.
例如
For instance,
你可以认为你父亲是个海盗 同时又是个好人 ...
you can accept that your father was a pirate and a good man
...或者你无法接受
or you can't.
孩子你有海盗血统
Pirate is in your blood,
所以你迟早会同流合污的
so you'll have to square with that someday.
而比如我
Now, me, for example.
我可以淹死你
I can let you drown.
但我无法单靠自己航行到特图加
But I can't bring this ship into Tortuga
懂吗?
all by me onesy, savvy?
所以...
So.
你能在一个海盗的指挥下开船...
Can you sail under the command of a pirate?
...还是不能?
Or can you not?
特图加?
Tortuga?
特图加
Tortuga.
更主要的是
More importantly, it is indeed a sad life
一个人从来没有领略过 特图加多姿多彩是令人悲伤的
that has never breathed deep this sweet bouquet
懂吗?
that is Tortuga, savvy?
你认为呢?
What do you think?
还算不错
lt'll linger.
让我来告诉你吧
I'll tell you, mate,
如果世界上每个城镇都像这样
if every town in the world were like this one,
将再没有人会感到失落
no man would ever feel unwanted.
斯卡赖特!
Scarlett!
这巴掌是给我的吗?
Not sure I deserved that.
吉塞尔!
Giselle!
她是谁?
Who was she?
什么?
What?
也许这巴掌是我活该被打的
I may have deserved that.
去死吧 你这个懒惰碎嘴的白痴!
Curse you for breathing, you slack-jawed idiot!
母爱!
Mother's love!
杰克!
Jack!
在弄醒一个人之前 你应该掂量清楚
You should know better than to wake a man when he's sleeping.
这会招来厄运的
It's bad luck.
啊 还好我懂得应付
Fortunately, I know how to counter it.
清醒的人
The man who did the waking
给迷迷糊糊的人买了杯酒
buys the man who was sleeping a drink.
迷迷糊糊的人一边喝酒
The man who was sleeping drinks while listening to a proposition
一边听着清醒人的建议
from the man who did the waking.
好的 那就开始吧
Aye, that'll about do it.
他妈的! 我已经醒了!
Blast! I'm already awake!
是为了清洗那种气味
That was for the smell.
留意周围!
Keep a sharp eye.
你在搞什么冒险?
Now, what's the nature of this venture of yourn?
我在找黑珍珠
I'm going after the Black Pearl,
我知道他要在哪里出现 所以我要去把它夺回来
I know where it's going to be, and I'm gonna take it.
杰克 这可是傻瓜干的事
Jack, it's a fool's errand.
你比我更了解黑珍珠的传说
You know better than me the tales of the Black Pearl,
这就是为什么我更了解巴博萨
That's why I know what Barbossa is up to.
我只要一船水手
All I need is a crew.
据闻巴博萨船长
From what I hear of Barbossa,
不会冒傻乎乎的险 也不会听人教唆
he's not a man to suffer fools, nor strike a bargain with one.
谢天谢地 我不是个傻瓜
I'd say it's a good thing I'm not a fool.
我可不信
Prove me wrong.
你凭什么认为巴博萨会还给你船?
What makes you think Barbossa will give up his ship to you?
可以说这是种互惠互利
Let's just say it's a matter of leverage.
那孩子?
The kid?
那是‘系带王’特纳的孩子
That is the child of Bootstrap Bill Turner.
他唯一的孩子 知道吗?
His only child, savvy?
现在还是唯一的?
Is he, now?
你说互惠互利
"Leverage," says you.
我说情况已变了
"l think I feel a change in the wind," says l.
我会找到船员的
I'll find us a crew.
一定有些像你一样疯狂的家伙
There's bound to be some sailors crazy as you.
只要有希望 就要尽全力
One can only hope.
用我们的生命
Take what you can.
去做赌注!
Give nothing back.
你将和船长共进晚餐
You'll be dining with the captain.
他要求你穿上这个
And he requests you wear this.
你告诉船长
You tell the captain
我不会听命于他的
that I am disinclined to acquiesce to his request.
他说你会这么说的
He said you'd say that.
他还说如果情况是那样
He also said, if that be the case,
你将和船员们共进晚餐
you'll be dining with the crew.
...一丝不挂的...
And you'll be naked.
很好
Fine.
这不是什么庆祝晚宴 也没必要顾及他人
There's no need to stand on ceremony, nor call to impress.
你一定很饿了
You must be hungry.
尝尝这酒
Try the wine.
还有苹果
And the apples.
来一个吧?
One of those next?
这有毒
It's poisoned.
杀死你特纳小姐是不合常理的
There would be no sense to be killing you.
那就放了我 你已经得到那件东西
Release me. You have your trinket.
我对你再也没用了
I'm of no further value to you.
你不知道这是什么 是吗?
You don't know what this is, do you?
这是海盗金币
It's a pirate medallion.
这是阿兹泰克金牌
This is Aztec gold.
882块相同的金牌之一
One of 882 identical pieces
原本是装在石箱运给科顿自己的
they delivered in a stone chest to Cortes himself.
这些钱是为了
Blood money paid to stem the slaughter
阻止他带领的军队屠杀的
he wreaked upon them with his armies.
但科顿贪得无厌
But the greed of Cortes was insatiable.
所以那些异教徒的神给这些金牌 下了可怕的咒语
So the heathen gods placed upon the gold a terrible curse.
只要任何人
Any mortal that removes
从石箱里仅拿出一块金牌
but a single piece from that stone chest
将被永远地惩罚
shall be punished for eternity.
我可不再信鬼怪的故事 巴博萨船长
I hardly believe in ghost stories anymore, Captain.
对的
Aye.
我们第一次听到这个传说的时候 我们也像你一样
That's exactly what I thought when we were told the tale.
金牌埋在一个无法找到的岛屿上
Buried on an island of dead what cannot be found,
除了那些知道地点的人
except for those who know where it is.
我们成功地找到了它们
Find it, we did.
石箱里
There be the chest.
装满了金牌
lnside be the gold.
我们把它们全部据为己有
And we took them all.
用来买东西 兑换
We spent them and traded them
我们将那些金子挥霍在酒食品
and frittered them away on drink and food
还有寻欢作乐上
and pleasurable company.
我们挥霍的越多 我们就越意识到
The more we gave them away, the more we came to realize,
美酒已经无法满足我们
the drink would not satisfy,
美食在我们的嘴里变成了灰尘
food turned to ash in our mouths,
这世上的所有的寻欢作乐
and all the pleasurable company in the world
都无法满足我们的欲望
could not slake our lust.
我们是被诅咒的人 特纳小姐
We are cursed men, Miss Turner.
被我们的贪婪驱使着 而现在我们却被它榨干
Compelled by greed, we were, but now we are consumed by it.
解除咒语的办法只有一个
There is one way we can end our curse.
把流落四方的阿兹泰克金币 全都收归一处
All the scattered pieces of the Aztec gold
还要以血还血
must be restored and the blood repaid.
真是多谢你了 最后的金币终于到手了
Thanks to ye, we have the final piece.
血债要血偿了?
And the blood to be repaid?
那就为什么我们现在 还不杀了你的原因
That's why there's no sense to be killin' you yet.
苹果要吗?
Apple?
啊!
Arr!
不要!
No!
我真的很好奇
I'm curious.
杀了我之后你还打算干啥?
After killing me, what is it you're planning on doing next?
瞧!
Look!
月光让我们原形毕露了
The moonlight shows us for what we really are.
我们算不上活人 自然也不可能死
We are not among the living, and so we cannot die.
但我们也不是死人
But neither are we dead.
太久太久了 我渴得要命却无法解渴
For too long I've been parched and unable to quench it.
太久太久了 我饿得要死却求死不能
Too long I've been starving to death and haven't died.
我毫无知觉
I feel nothing.
风吹到脸上 浪打到身上都没有一丝感觉
Not the wind on my face nor the spray of the sea
更别说温香软玉的女人了
nor the warmth of a woman's flesh.
你最好开始相信那些鬼故事吧 特纳小姐
You best start believing in ghost stories, Miss Turner.
因为你正置身其中!
You're in one!
你们看什么看? 回去干活!
What are you looking at? Back to work!
一饱眼福吧 我的船长
Feast your eyes, Captain.
这儿站着的 全都是忠心耿耿的好水手
All of them faithful hands before the mast.
全都是吃这碗饭长大的
Every man worth his salt.
而且全都够疯的
And crazy to boot.
他们就是你身强力壮的船员吗?
So this is your able-bodied crew?
- 你 伙计! - 科顿 先生!
- You, sailor! - Cotton, sir.
科顿先生 你有服从命令的勇气和毅力
Mr. Cotton, do you have the courage to follow orders
即便面对危险和死亡也忠心不二吗?
and stay true in the face of danger and death?
科顿先生! 请回答我!
Mr. Cotton! Answer, man!
他是个哑巴.可怜的家伙舌头被人割了
He's a mute. Poor devil had his tongue cut out.
所以他训练了一只鹦鹉来代他说话
He trained the parrot to talk for him.
他是怎么办到的谁也不知道
No one's yet figured how.
科顿先生的鹦鹉!
Mr. Cotton's parrot.
这个问题你来答
Same question.
顺风! 顺风!
Wind in the sails! Wind in the sails!
我们一般就当这个是"是的"的意思
Mostly we figure that means "yes."
当然是这个意思
Of course it does.
你满意了?
Satisfied?
你证明了他们是一帮疯子
Well, you've proved they're mad.
我们有啥好处啊?
And what's the benefit for us?
玛利亚啊!
Anamaria.
我想你这巴掌你又挨冤枉了吧?
I suppose you didn't deserve that.
没有 这不冤枉
No, that one I deserved.
你偷了我的船!
You stole my boat!
其实...
Actually ...
只是借用一下 未经允许的借用
Borrowed. Borrowed without permission.
但一心一意要还给你的
But with every intention of bringing it back.
可你还了吗? !
But you didn't!
我会另还一艘给你的
You'll get another one.
那当然
I will.
一艘更好的
A better one.
一艘更好的!
A better one!
那艘!
That one.
哪艘?
What one?
那艘?
That one?
好吧! 就那艘
Aye, that one.
- 你们怎么说? - 赞成!
- What say you? - Aye!
好耶!
Aye!
下锚!
Anchors aweigh!
不不不不 带女人上船会很走霉运的
No, no, it's frightful bad luck to bring a woman aboard, sir.
不带上她会更倒霉的
lt'll be far worse not to have her.
用这么一个破指南针
How can we sail to an island that nobody can find
我们怎么可能驶到 那个没人能找到的小岛啊?
with a compass that doesn't work?
没错 这指南针是不指南了
Aye, the compass doesn't point North,
可我们也不是要找南在那儿啊 对不对?
but we're not trying to find North, are we?
我们得撤帆了
We should drop canvas, sir.
再坚持一会儿
She can hold a bit longer.
你都是怎么想的才能这么乐观啊 船长?
What's in your head that's put you in such a fine mood?
我们会赶上他们的
We're catching up.
该上路了 乖乖!
Time to go, poppet.
喔! 喔! 喔! 喔!
Ho! Ho! Ho! Ho! Ho! Ho!
死人不说谎
Dead men tell no tales.
好恐怖的地方
Puts a chill in the bones
这条航道要了多少好水手的命啊
how many honest sailors have been claimed by this passage.
杰克的那个指南针怎么来的你知道吗?
How is it that Jack came by that compass?
杰克 斯派洛上特图加岛以前的事很少有人知道
Not a lot's known about Jack fore he showed up in Tortuga
他当时是一心追寻死亡之岛屿的财宝去的
with a mind to go after the treasure of the lsla de Muerta.
我是后来才认识他的
That was before I'd met him.
他当黑珍珠号船长的时候
Back when he was Captain of the Black Pearl,
什么?
What?
他从来没提到过
He failed to mention that.
他现在行事谨慎多了
He plays things closer to the vest now.
很不容易学到的啊!
And a hard-learned lesson it was.
经过三天的探宝 船上的大副来找他说
Three days out, the first mate comes to him
他们得的财宝应该平分
and says everything's an equal share.
藏宝点也一样
That should mean the location of the treasure.
杰克给搞蒙了
Jack gives up the bearings.
当夜却发生了叛乱
That night, there was a mutiny.
杰克被弃置在一个荒岛上等死
They marooned Jack on an island and left him to die,
但是他还没死就被热疯了
but not before he'd gone mad with the heat.
啊 这就是为什么他有点...
So that's the reason for all the...
跟这根本扯不上关系
Reason's got nothing to do with it.
你知道吗 威尔 被弃置在荒岛的海盗
Now, Will, when a pirate's marooned,
通常都会给他一把枪的 枪里只有一颗子弹
he's a given a pistol with a single shot. One shot.
是的 用来打猎和求助都没太大用的
Well, that won't do much good hunting or to be rescued.
可又饥又渴三个星期下来
But after three weeks of a starving belly and thirst,
那枪看起来就象个解脱的诱惑了
that pistol will start to look real friendly.
但是杰克从荒岛脱了身 并且仍然留着那一颗子弹
But Jack escaped the island, and he still has that single shot.
哦 他那颗子弹是留给
Oh, he won't use it, though, save on one man.
背叛他的大副的
His mutinous first mate.
- 是巴博萨? - 没错
- Barbossa. - Aye.
杰克怎么从荒岛上逃出来的?
How did Jack get off the island?
好的 我来告诉你
Well, I'll tell ye.
他走进了一个浅滩
He waded out into the shallows.
在那儿呆了三天三夜
He waited there three days and three nights
直到每种海洋生物
till all manner of sea creatures
都对他的存在习以为常了
'came acclimated to his presence.
在第四天早上
And on the fourth morning,
他用绳子捆住了几只海龟
he roped a couple of sea turtles,
把它们扎成了个筏子
lashed them together, and made a raft.
他用绳子捆住了几只海龟?
He roped a couple of sea turtles?
没错 是海龟
Aye, sea turtles.
他哪来的绳子?
What did he use for rope?
用人的头发
Human hair.
我背上的
From my back.
下锚!
Let go the anchor!
是的 船长!
Aye, Captain, aye!
小特纳和我上岸去
Young Mr. Turner and l are to go ashore.
船长! 要是最糟的情况发生了怎么办?
Captain, what if the worst should happen?
按法典办
Keep to the Code.
是 按法典
Aye, the Code.
走
Move.
我们集了十年的宝贝啊
10 years of hoarding swag.
终于等到了可以享用的时候了
And now we finally get to spend it.
一旦解除了咒语 我们就成了阔佬啦
Once we're quit of the curse, we'll be rich men.
你也可以买个大小合适的玻璃眼珠了
You can buy an eye what actually fits and is made of glass.
这玩艺儿真刺的好难受啊
This one does splinter something terrible.
别摸它了
Stop rubbing it.
他说的最糟的情况发生时 要守的规矩是什么啊?
What Code is Gibbs to keep to if the worst should happen?
海盗法典
Pirate's Code.
对落了单的人我们是弃之不顾的
Any man who falls behind is left behind.
海盗没有英雄?
No heroes amongst thieves?
当你把海盗们看透的时候
For having such a bleak outlook on pirates,
你自己就快成为其中一员了
you're well on your way to becoming one.
撬开牢门救了个囚犯
Sprung a man from jail,
不问自取开走了皇家舰队的一艘船
commandeered a ship of the fleet,
和一帮海盗船员扬帆驶到特图加岛
sailed with a buccaneer crew out of Tortuga.
还被财宝完全迷倒
And you're completely obsessed with treasure.
这是胡说 我才没被财宝迷住呢
That's not true. I am not obsessed with treasure.
财宝指的可不光是金子银子 哥们
Not all treasure is silver and gold, mate.
先生们 这天我们终于来临了!
Gentlemen, the time has come!.
我们的解救就在前方!
Our salvation is nigh!
我们的苦难就快到头了!
Our torment is near an end.
伊丽莎白
Elizabeth.
十年来我们受尽了考验和试探
For 10 years we've been tested and tried,
我们在场的每个人
and each man jack of you here
都无数次地证明了自己的勇气
has proved his mettle a hundred times over
无数次啊!
and a hundred times again!
我们可受够了!
Suffered, I have!
我们已经受够了惩罚
Punished, we were, the lot of us.
简直比我们所犯下的罪还要多得多!
Disproportionate to our crime!
这罪行就在这儿!
Here it is!
这下了咒语的科顿的宝藏
The cursed treasure of Cortes himself.
每一枚散落在外的金币 我们都找回来了
Every last piece that went astray, we have returned.
除了这一枚
Save for this.
杰克!
Jack!
现在还不行 我们要等最佳时机
Not yet. We wait for the opportune moment.
我们找到了881个 但在找最后一个时 我们一次又一次地绝望了
881 we found, but despaired of ever finding the last.
那要到什么时候?
When's that?
到你最有利可图的时候吗?
When it's of greatest profit to you?
我能问你个问题吗?
May I ask you something?
我给过你任何觉得 我不可信赖的理由吗?
Have I ever given you reason not to trust me?
帮帮忙好吗?
Do us a favor.
我知道这对你是桩难事 但拜托你就呆在这儿
I know it's difficult for you, but please stay here
别做任何傻事
and try not to do anything stupid.
在我们中 有谁已为信奉邪神偿清血祭?
And who among us has paid the blood sacrifice owed to the heathen gods?
我们!
Us!
那么还有谁的血尚未献祭?
And whose blood must yet be paid?
她的!
Hers!
你知道吗 等诅咒解除之后
You know the first thing I'm gonna do
我要做的第一件事是什么吗?
after the curse is lifted?
就是吃掉整整一堆苹果
Eat a whole bushel of apples.
血的咒语
Begun by blood.
要以血解开
By blood undone.
对不起 杰克 我可不想被你利用
Sorry, Jack. I'm not gonna be your leverage.
就这样?
That's it?
一点都别浪费
Waste not.
有作用吗?
Did it work?
- 我没感觉有什么变化啊? - 我们如何判断呢?
- I don't feel no different. - How do we tell?
你没有死
You're not dead.
没有
No.
他居然开枪射我!
He shot me!
没有起作用!
It didn't work.
我们身上的诅咒还在!
The curse it still upon us!
你 姑娘! 你的父亲叫什么名字?
You, maid! Your father, what was his name?
你父亲是不是叫威廉 特纳?
Was your father William Turner?
不
No.
那个八年前坐船 离开英格兰的孩子在哪儿?
Where's his child that sailed from England eight years ago?
那个具有威廉 特纳血统的孩子?
The child in whose veins flows the blood of William Turner?
你们两个!
You two!
你们俩给我们找了个冒牌货!
You brought us the wrong person!
不!
No!
她有那块金币 而且她年纪也正相当
She had the medallion. She's the proper age.
她说她的名字叫特纳
She said her name was Turner.
她说谎
I think she lied to us.
你让我们来这里白跑一趟!
You brought us here for nothing.
我不想问也不想再猜了 提格
I won't take questioning or second guesses from you, Twigg.
你想推脱责任?
Who's to blame?
你所做的每个决定 都让我们的情况变得更糟
Every decision you've made has led us from bad to worse.
是你把系带王推进了深渊!
It was you who sent Bootstrap to the depths!
对!
Yeah!
又是你把我们带到这里来!
And it's you who brought us here in the first place.
这里有哪个懦夫敢挑战我的 上来开口啊!
If any coward here dare challenge me, let him speak!
依我看 我们不妨割断她的喉咙把血放光
I say we cut her throat and spill all her blood,
也许那样有效
just in case.
对啊!
Yeah!
金币!
The medallion!
她拿走了金币!
She's taken it!
快去追她 你们这群忘恩负义的东西!
Get after her, you feckless pack of ingrates!
桨都不见了!
No oars here!
桨呢?
Where's the oars?
桨都不见了!
The oars have gone missing.
快找!
Find them!
快去找桨!
Find the oars!
你
You.
你应该是死了!
You're supposed to be dead!
我没有死吗?
Am I not?
帕鲁类!
Palulay.
帕鲁-力-拉-拉-鲁鲁
Palu-li-la-la-lulu.
帕力力
Parlili.
帕思力 帕思勒 帕特 帕特
Parsnip, parsley, partner, partner.
帕雷?
Parley?
没错 帕雷!
That's the one! Parley!
帕雷!
Parley!
帕雷?
Parley?
见鬼 是谁想出"帕雷"这个点子来的?
Damn to the depths whatever man that thought up "parley"!
大概是法国佬吧
That would be the French.
别又是海盗啊!
Not more pirates.
欢迎上船 伊丽莎白小姐
Welcome aboard, Miss Elizabeth.
吉布斯先生?
Mr. Gibbs?
嗨 孩子! 杰克在哪里?
Hey, boy, where be Jack?
杰克?
Jack?
杰克 斯派洛?
Jack Sparrow?
他落在后面了
He fell behind.
按规矩行事!
Keep to the Code.
起锚!
Weigh anchor!
升帆! 动作快点
Hoist the sails! Make quick!
你这个该死的东西 是怎么逃离那荒岛的?
How the blazes did you get off that island?
当你把我放逐到 那个荒凉的小岛上时
When you marooned me on that godforsaken spit of land,
你忘记了一件非常重要的事情 朋友
you forgot one very important thing, mate.
我是杰克 斯派洛船长
I'm Captain Jack Sparrow.
哦 好吧 我不会再犯同样的错误
Well, I won't be making that mistake again.
先生们 你们还记得杰克斯派洛船长吗?
Gents, you all remember Captain Jack Sparrow?
对啊!
Aye.
杀了他!
Kill him.
那女孩的血没有用 对不对?
The girl's blood didn't work, did it?
别开枪!
Hold your fire!
你知道谁才是我们要找的人?
You know whose blood we need.
我知道你们要找的人
I know whose blood you need.
什么样的人会以命换船?
What sort of a man trades a man's life for a ship?
海盗
Pirate.
这个让我来吧
Here. Let me.
谢谢你
Thank you.
你在巴博萨面前冒用我的名字
You said you gave Barbossa my name as yours.
为什么?
Why?
我不知道
I don't know.
我很抱歉 铁匠的手都这样 很粗糙
I'm sorry. Blacksmith's hands. I know they're rough.
不...我的意思是 他们的确粗糙...
No. I mean yes, they are, but...
但你不用停下来
But don't stop.
伊丽莎白
Elizabeth.
这是你的
It's yours.
我还以为他们救我上来那天弄丢了
I thought I'd lost it the day they rescued me.
那是我父亲的礼物
It was a gift from my father.
他给了我
He sent it to me.
你为什么拿走它?
Why did you take it?
因为我担心你是一个海盗
Because I was afraid that you were a pirate.
那太可怕了
That would have been awful.
他们要的不是你的血...
It wasn't your blood they needed.
而是我父亲的血...
It was my father's blood.
我的血
My blood.
一个海盗的血
The blood of a pirate.
我很抱歉 请原谅我
Will, I'm so sorry. Please forgive me.
那么你打算告诉我那个人的名字
You expect to leave me on some beach
然后把我留在岸上
with nothing but a name and your word it's the one I need
然后我就这样 看你开着我的船扬长而去?
and watch you sail away in my ship?
不
No.
我打算把你先丢到岸上
I expect to leave you standing on some beach
什么也不告诉你
with absolutely no name at all,
等到我开船走远后
watching me sail away on my ship,
我才会把那个名字喊给你听
and then I'll shout the name back to you.
懂了吗?
Savvy?
但是如果我站在沙滩上听你叫喊
That still leaves the problem of me on some beach
也许根本就听不到我要找的
with naught but a name and your word
那人的名字
it's the one I need.
在我们俩之间
Of the two of us,
只有我是没有参与叛变的人
I'm the only one who hasn't committed mutiny.
因此我的话值得相信
Therefore, my word is the one we'll be trusting.
不过 我想我还是应该谢谢你
Although, I suppose I should be thanking you because, in fact,
如果不是你出卖了我 把我丢在荒岛上
if you hadn't betrayed me and left me to die,
我也许会和你们一同 承受那可怕的诅咒
I would have an equal share in that curse, same as you.
这真是个有趣的世界 对吗?
Funny old world, isn't it?
船长 我们追上阻击者号了
Captain, we're coming up on the Interceptor,
我有个建议 巴博萨
I'm having a thought here, Barbossa.
我们先暂时升起休战旗如何?
What say we run up a flag of truce,
我到阻击者号上去
I scurry over to the Interceptor,
和他们谈判拿回你的金币 好不好?
and I negotiate the return of your medallion?
杰克 现在你应该明白 正是这种软弱让你失去了黑珍珠
Now, that's exactly the attitude that lost you the Pearl,
等人死了以后再找他们就容易多了
People are easy to search when they're dead.
把他关进禁闭室!
Lock him in the brig.
把帆全张开!
Hands aloft to loose t'gallants!
在这样这样风力下 它很容易就能赶上我们的!
With this wind, she'll carry every sail we've got!
怎么了?
What's happening?
黑珍珠号 她赶上我们了
The Black Pearl, She's gaining on us.
这是加勒比海上速度最快的船
This is the fastest ship in the Caribbean.
等他们抓住我们以后你再说这些吧
You can tell them that after they've caught us.
我们的船吃水浅 对不对?
We're shallower on the draft?
是的
Aye.
那为什么不逃进那片沙洲甩掉他们?
Well, then can't we lose them amongst those shoals?
他们用不了多久就会追上来 我们赶不到
We don't have to outrun them long, just long enough.
减轻负重 从船头到船尾!
Lighten the ship, stem to stern!
把能丢的都丢掉 就当损失好了
Anything we can afford to lose, see that it's lost.
显然这里漏水
Apparently, there's a leak.
拉起主帆横索 大炮准备
Haul on the main brace! Make ready the guns!
伸出长桨!
And run out the sweeps.
- 拉! - 呼!
- Pull! - Ho!
看来我们真要干一场
We're gonna need that.
到现在看来
It was a good plan.
这仍然是个好计划
Up till now.
吉布斯!
Gibbs!
我们要坚定自己的立场
We have to make a stand.
我们必须战斗!
We must fight!
大炮装弹!
Load the guns!
用什么?
With what?
任何东西 所有东西!
Anything. Everything!
只要是我们手上还有的
Anything we have left.
装弹!
Load the guns!
容器或者是钉弹!
Case shot and langrage!
钉子和碎玻璃片!
Nails and crushed glass!
随你们便
With a will!
黑珍珠很快就要 从左舷船尾赶上来了
The Pearl's gonna luff up on our port quarter!
她会毫不费力地把我们撞个稀烂!
She'll rake us without ever presenting a target.
右边船舷下锚!
Lower the anchor on the right side.
右边船舷!
On the starboard side!
这招肯定能让他们大吃一惊
It has the element of surprise.
你蠢到家了 小姐! 你们俩都是
You're daft, lady! You both are!
就像杰克一样愚蠢
Daft like Jack!
右舷下锚!
Lower the starboard anchor!
混蛋快动 否则就把你们也装进大炮里!
Do it, you dogs, or it's you we'll load into the cannons!
放舵!
Let go!
他们在放锚急转!
They're clubhauling!
左舷急转! 收回右舷长桨!
Hard to port! Rack the starboard oars.
左舷急转!
Hard to port!
大家都站稳了!
Keep us steady, man.
开火!
Now!
Fire!
开火!
Fire all!
别把我的船打得满是窟窿!
Stop blowing holes in my ship!
快想点更好的办法 小姑娘!
We could use a few more ideas, lass.
该你了!
Your turn.
我们需要有恶魔一般的天份
We need us a devil's dowry.
我们可以把她交出去
We'll give them her.
他们的目标不是她
She's not what they're after.
金币
The medallion.
现出你们的真功夫来吧!
Raise your colors, you bloomin' cockroaches!
水手们! 准备格斗!
Hands, grapnels, at the ready.
接舷战!
Prepare to board!
把他们炸个粉碎吧!
Blast all to carcasses, men!
去炸他们的弹药舱
Forward clear to the powder magazine.
其它人把金币给我抢回来!
And the rest of you, bring me that medallion!
喂!
Help!
Hey!
下面!
Below!
非常感谢
Thanks very much.
杰克!
Jack!
酒壶都空了
Bloody empty.
诶!
Aaah!
这样很不文雅
That's not very nice.
金币在哪里?
Where's the medallion?
下流胚!
Wretch!
亲爱的威廉在哪里?
Where's dear William?
威尔!
Will!
伊丽莎白!
Elizabeth!
猴子!
Monkey!
我搬不动它!
I can't move it!
快点!
Come on!
威尔!
Will!
伊丽莎白!
Elizabeth!
我们都很感谢你 杰克
Why, thank you, Jack.
别客气
You're welcome.
不是说你 我们的这只猴子也叫杰克
Not you. We named the monkey "Jack."
先生们 我们的希望又回来了!
Gents, our hope is restored!
你们如果还想要求帕雷的权利的话
Any of you so much as thinks the word "parley,"
我就一枪毙了你们!
I'll have your guts for garters.
威尔!
Will!
你一定要去阻止它!
You've got to stop it!
- 住手! - 欢迎回来 小姐
- Stop it! - Welcome back, miss.
上次你卑劣地利用了 我们的盛情好客
You took advantage of our hospitality last time.
现在你也该得到回报 这很公平
It holds fair now you return the favor.
巴博萨!
Barbossa!
威尔!
Will.
放她走!
She goes free.
孩子 你想怎么样!
What's in your head, boy?
放她走!
She goes free!
你只有一发子弹 可我们都是不死之躯
You've only got one shot, and we can't die.
别做蠢事
Don't do anything stupid.
你们不会
You can't.
但我会
I can.
没错
Like that.
你是谁?
Who are you?
无名小辈 他是个小人物
No one. He's no one.
我婶婶的一个远房表亲的侄儿
A distant cousin of my aunt's nephew twice removed.
不过他唱歌很好听 是个娘娘腔
Lovely singing voice, though. Eunuch.
我的名字叫威尔 特纳
My name is Will Turner.
我的父亲是比尔 特纳
My father was Bootstrap Bill Turner.
我的血管里流淌着他的血液
His blood runs in my veins.
他就是比尔的儿子
He's the spitting image of old Bootstrap Bill
那个总是缠着我们的比尔
come back to haunt us.
按我说的做 否则我就扣扳机
On my word, do as I say, or I'll pull this trigger
然后就消失在这茫茫大海里
and be lost to Davy Jones' locker.
说说你的条件 特纳先生
Name your terms, Mr. Turner.
放伊丽莎白走
Elizabeth goes free.
好 我们知道了 还有别的条件吗?
Yes, we know that one. Anything else?
还有船员 不许伤害他们
And the crew. The crew are not to be harmed.
同意
Agreed.
乖孩子 快走!
Go on, poppet, go!
走上去!
Walk the plank!
巴博萨 你这个撒谎的杂种! 你答应了放她走
Barbossa, you lying bastard! You swore she'd go free!
别诋毁我的信誉 孩子
Don't dare impugn me honor, boy.
我是同意放她走
I agreed she'd go free,
可你也没说在什么地方和什么时候
but it was you who failed to specify when or where.
不过失去这样一位尤物 实在令人惋惜 是不是?
Though does seem a shame to lose something so fine, don't it?
是的
Aye.
在你走之前能把衣服还给我吗?
So I'll be having that dress back before you go.
我一直都很喜欢你
I always liked you.
见你的鬼去吧
Goes with your black heart.
噢 还带点体温
Ooh, it's still warm.
你快跳啊!
Off you go!
快点!
Come on!
真麻烦!
Too long!
我真心希望大家能够尽释前嫌
I'd really rather hoped we were past all this.
杰克 杰克
Jack...
你还没有注意到吗?
Did you not notice?
这就是当初我们把 你丢下的那个小岛
That be the same island we made you governor of on our last little trip.
没错
I did notice.
也许你能再创一次
Perhaps you'll be able to conjure up
死里逃生的奇迹
another miraculous escape.
但我表示非常怀疑
But I doubt it.
跳下去
Off you go.
跳
Yeah.
上次你给我留了一把单发手枪
Last time, you left me a pistol with one shot.
老天爷 对啊
By the powers, you're right.
杰克的枪在那里 拿过来
Where be Jack's pistol? Bring it forward.
考虑到我们有两个人
Seeing as there's two of us, a gentleman would give us
一位绅士也许应该给我两把枪
a pair of pistols.
和以前一样 只有一把枪
lt'll be one pistol as before,
你尽可以扮演绅士先把那位女士打死
You can be the gentleman and shoot the lady
然后自己也饿死
and starve to death yourself.
这是我第二次
That's the second time
眼看着有人开走我的船
I've had to watch that man sail away with my ship.
你以前也被放逐到这个岛上 对吗?
But you were marooned on this island before.
我们仍可以用你当初的法子逃跑
We can escape the same way you did.
那样又有什么用呢 小姐?
To what point and purpose, young missy?
黑珍珠已经开走了
The Black Pearl is gone.
除非在你的衣服里 还藏着一个舵轮和几张帆
Unless you have a rudder and sails hidden in that bodice.
看来那是不太可能的
Unlikely.
而在我们追上他们之前 小特纳大概早死了
Young Mr. Turner will be dead long before you can reach him.
可你是杰克 斯派洛船长
But you're Captain Jack Sparrow.
你能在东印度公司的 7个特工眼皮子底下溜掉
You vanished from seven agents of the East lndia Company.
你不费一枪一弹就洗劫了整个拿骚港
You sacked Nassau Port without even firing a shot.
你真的还是我所知道的那个大海盗吗?
Are you the pirate I've read about or not?
你上次是怎么逃脱的?
How did you escape last time?
上一次... 我在这里只待了三天 明白吗?
Last time, I was here a grand total of three days, all right?
上一次...
Last time...
走私酒贩子们把这座岛 当成一个秘密仓库
The rumrunners used this island as a cache,
他们来到这里装货 我好求歹求终于才能搭船离开
came by, and I was able to barter passage off.
从这些东西的情况来看
From the looks of things,
这里已经很久没有人来过了
they've long been out of business.
也许这都要归功于你那位朋友 诺灵顿
Probably have your bloody friend Norrington to thank for that.
那么就是这样了?
So that's it, then?
这就是伟大的杰克 斯派洛
That's the secret grand adventure
所谓的惊天动地的冒险经历?
of the infamous Jack Sparrow?
你在沙滩上躺了三天 喝着兰姆酒!
You spent three days lying on a beach, drinking rum?
欢迎来到加勒比 亲爱的
Welcome to the Caribbean, love.
∮ 我们是恶魔和黑绵羊 ∮
∮ We're devils, we're black sheep ∮
∮ 我们是地地道道的大坏蛋 ∮
∮ We're really bad eggs ∮
∮ 让我一醉解千愁! ∮
∮ Drink up, me hearties, yo ho ∮
∮ 哟吼 ∮
∮ Yo ho, yo ho ∮
噢!
Ouch!
∮ 为我的海盗生涯而欢呼! ∮
∮ A pirate's life for me ∮
我喜欢这首歌!
I love this song!
地地道道的大坏蛋!
Really bad eggs!
哦!
Ooh.
当我夺回黑珍珠之后
When I get the Pearl back,
我要教会每个船员都唱它
I'm gonna teach it to the whole crew.
我们要随时随地唱它
We'll sing it all the time.
那样你就会成为西班牙大陆上 家喻户晓的海盗
You'll be the most fearsome pirate in the Spanish Main.
不只是西班牙 亲爱的
Not just the Spanish Main, love.
整个海洋
The entire ocean.
整个世界
The entire world.
我们想去哪里就去哪里 这就是船的真正含义 你明白吗?
Wherever we want to go, we go. That's what a ship is, you know.
可不仅仅是有条龙骨 有个船壳 有层甲板 有几张船上所必需的帆
It's not just a keel and a deck and sails.
一艘船的真正含义
That's what a ship needs.
黑珍珠真正的含义
But what a ship is, what the Black Pearl really is,
是自由
is freedom.
杰克 当你被困在这岛上时
Jack, it must be really terrible for you
那种感觉一定非常可怕
to be trapped on this island.
噢 对啊
Oh, yes.
但这次比上次好多了 有个伴了
But the company is infinitely better than last time,
而且我觉得
I think.
风景也优美多了
The scenery has definitely improved.
- 斯派洛先生 - 嗯?
- Mr. Sparrow. - Mm-hmm?
我还没有醉到
I'm not entirely sure I've had enough rum
想听你这些陈词滥调
to allow that kind of talk.
我知道你什么意思 亲爱的
I know exactly what you mean, love.
为了自由!
To freedom.
为了黑珍珠!
To the Black Pearl,
不 不好!
No! Not good!
住手! 不好!
Stop! Not good!
你在干什么?
What are you doing?
你把所有的货物都烧了 整个酒窖 兰姆酒!
You burned all the food, the shade! The rum!
对 没有兰姆酒了
Yes, the rum is gone.
为什么不要兰姆酒了?
Why is the rum gone?
第一 因为这种邪恶的饮料
One, because it is a vile drink
可以把最受尊敬的人 彻底变成一个恶棍
that turns even the most respectable men into scoundrels.
第二 燃烧的烟火 可以升到上千英尺高
Two, that signal is over a thousand feet high.
而整个皇家海军都在找我
The entire Royal Navy is looking for me.
难道你以为他们不会看到?
Do you think there is the slightest chance they won't see?
但是为什么要把兰姆酒也烧了?
But why is the rum gone?
只管等待吧 斯派洛船长
Just wait, Captain Sparrow.
你给我注意看一个小时 也许两个小时 以你的眼力 你很快就会发现
You give it one hour, maybe two, and you will see
水平线上的白色船帆
white sails on that horizon.
"当你被困在这岛上时 一定感觉非常可怕 杰克"
"Must've been terrible for you to be trapped here, Jack."
现在才是真的可怕!
Well, it bloody is now!
这次以后再也不想跟她打交道了
There'll be no living with her after this.
- 但我们必须去救威尔! - 不!
- But we've got to save Will. - No.
你现在已经安全了
You're safe now.
我们要立刻返回罗耶港
We will return to Port Royal,
而不是和海盗们搅到一起!
not go gallivanting after pirates!
我们把他推向了死亡
Then we condemn him to death.
这孩子的结局令人惋惜
The boy's fate is regrettable,
他自甘堕落 卷入了海盗们的肮脏勾当
but so was his decision to engage in piracy.
他是为了救我 为了不让我受折磨!
To rescue me. To prevent anything from happening to me.
请允许我斗胆插入 一点专业人士的看法
If I may be so bold as to inject my professional opinion.
黑珍珠在那次战斗以后已经是千疮百孔
The Pearl was listing near to scuppers after the battle.
这是她最虚弱的时候
It's very unlikely she'll be able to make good time.
再考虑一下吧
Think about it.
黑珍珠号
The Black Pearl,
加勒比海上的最后一艘海盗船 朋友
The last real pirate threat in the Caribbean, mate.
你会错过这个机会吗?
How can you pass that up, right?
斯派洛先生 我是在尽职效忠
By remembering that I serve others, Mr. Sparrow.
而不是为我自己
Not only myself.
司令官 我求你了 拜托了
Commodore, I beg you, please do this.
为了我
For me.
就当是求婚的彩礼吧
As a wedding gift.
伊丽莎白
Elizabeth.
你接受司令官的求婚了?
Are you accepting the commodore's proposal?
我接受
I am.
一场婚礼! 我爱婚礼!
A wedding! I love weddings!
大家喝个痛快!
Drinks all around!
我了解
I know.
"把他拷起来" 对吗?
"Clap him in irons," right?
斯派洛先生 你要到掌舵水手那里去
Mr. Sparrow, you will accompany these fine men to the helm
帮助他们找到通往乱礁的方向
and provide us with a bearing to lsla de Muerta.
在旅途中闲下来的时候
You will spend the rest of the voyage
你最好多想想这句话的含义
contemplating all meanings of the phrase
"沉默是金"
"silent as the grave."
你听清楚我的话了吗?
Do I make myself clear?
简直不能再清楚了
lnescapably clear.
龙骨触礁!
Shiver me timbers.
科顿说你弄歪了
Cotton here says you missed a bit.
你认识威廉 特纳?
You knew William Turner?
老比尔
Ol' Bootstrap Bill.
我们认识他
We knew him.
如果我们像对杰克斯派洛那样反叛布斯特拉普 这辈子都别想过安稳日子
Never sat well with Bootstrap, what we did to Jack Sparrow.
不管是叛变还是其他什么
The mutiny and all.
他总说这不符合法典的规定
He said it wasn't right with the Code.
所以他把一块金币给了你
That's why he sent off a piece of the treasure to you.
他说我们活该受到诅咒
He said we deserved to be cursed.
而且永远不能被解脱
And remain cursed.
一个笨蛋
Stupid blighter.
大好人
Good man.
但你可以想象
Well, as you can imagine,
和船长在一起的日子也不好过
that didn't sit too well with the captain.
和船长在一起的日子更糟糕
That didn't sit too well with the captain at all.
- 告诉他巴博萨干了些什么! - 是我在说这个故事!
- Tell him what Barbossa did. - I'm telling the story!
所以...船长干了件事
So, what the captain did.
他把老比尔捆在一尊铁炮上
He strapped a cannon to Bootstrap's bootstraps.
那是我们最后一次看到老比尔 特纳
And last we saw of Ol' Bill Turner,
他就这么沉进了汪洋大海里
he was sinking to the crushing, black oblivion of Davy Jones' locker.
而在那之后不久
'Course it was only after that
我们就发现只有他的血 才能拯救我们脱离诅咒
we learned we needed his blood to lift the curse.
这真是太讽刺了
That's what you call ironic.
带他出来!
Bring him.
我可不喜欢这里的地形
I don't care for the situation.
任何想冲进洞穴的人都会遭到伏击
Any attempt to storm the caves could turn to an ambush.
如果你是伏击者就不会那么悲观了
Not if you're the one doing the ambushing.
我进去劝说巴博萨 和他的手下出来上小船
I convince Barbossa to send his men out with their little boats.
你和你的人
You and your mates return to the Dauntless
回无畏号开炮轰他们 好吗?
and blast the bejesus out of them with your little cannons.
你会有什么损失呢?
What do you have to lose?
我没什么好担心的
Nothing I'd lament being rid of.
现在 我有句话想坦诚相告...
Now, to be quite honest with you,
那些还在无畏者号上的人 可能会有危险
there's a risk to those aboard the Dauntless,
其中包括未来的司令夫人
which includes the future Mrs. Commodore.
抱歉 为了您的安全
Sorry, but it's for your own safety.
我可不管司令官下了什么命令 我必须告诉他
The commodore ordered! I have to tell him!
那些海盗!
The pirates!
他们被诅咒了! 他们是不死之躯!
They're cursed! They can't be killed!
别担心 小姐 他已经知道了
Don't worry. He's informed of that.
有只美人鱼跳到甲板上来 把一切都告诉了他
A mermaid flopped up on deck and told him the whole story.
这都是杰克 斯派洛的阴谋
This is Jack Sparrow's doing!
别担心
No reason to fret.
只是割破手指头放点血而已
Just a prick of the finger. A few drops of blood.
这次别再犯错了
No mistakes this time.
他只能算半个特纳 我们给他来个大放血!
He's only half Turner. We spill it all!
看来真有点担心的理由
Guess there is reason to fret.
麻烦借光
Beg your pardon. Beg your pardon.
- 因血而起... - 打扰了
- Begun by blood. - Excuse me.
由血而...
By blood ...
杰克!
Jack!
不可能
It's not possible.
不太可能
Not probable.
伊丽莎白在哪里?
Where's Elizabeth?
她很安全 正如我所保证的那样
She's safe, just like I promised.
她正准备嫁给诺灵顿 正如她所许诺的那样
She's set to marry Norrington, like she promised.
而你就得要为她而死 正如你所许诺的那样
You get to die for her, like you promised.
所以说我们都是些信守诺言的男子汉
So we're all men of our word, really.
不过要排除伊丽莎白在外 因为她是个女人
Except for Elizabeth who is, in fact, a woman.
闭嘴 你就是下一个!
Shut up! You're next.
你不该那样做 伙计
You don't want to be doing that, mate.
不 我认为我应该
No, I really think I do.
你的葬礼而已
Your funeral.
为什么我不该那样做?
Why don't I want to be doing it?
嗯 因为...
Well, because...
因为无畏号 皇家海军的骄傲
Because the HMS Dauntless, pride of the Royal Navy,
此刻正停泊在外面
is floating just offshore, waiting for you.
我们在这里做什么?
What we doing here?
等海盗们出来...打他们个措手不及
The pirates come out, unprepared and unawares.
利用交叉火力放倒他们 送他们回老家
We catch them in a crossfire, send them down to see Old Hob.
我知道我们来这里的原因
I know why we're here.
我是说 为什么我们 不照斯派洛先生说的行事
I meant, why aren't we doing
用大炮一劳永逸解决他们?
what Mr. Sparrow said we should do with the cannons and all?
因为那是斯派洛说的话
Because it was Mr. Sparrow who said it.
你以为他说的是真话吗?
You think he wasn't telling the truth?
请听我说 伙计
Just hear me out, mate.
你命令你的手下潜水登上无畏者号
You order your men to row to the Dauntless,
让他们放开手脚大干一场
They do what they do best.
鱼归鱼 虾归虾
Robert's your uncle. Fannie's your aunt.
这样你就有两艘船
There you are with two ships.
拥有自己的舰队了
The makings of your very own fleet.
当然你可以选大船当旗舰 有谁会和你争呢?
You'll take the grandest as your flagship, and who's to argue?
可是黑珍珠怎么办?
But what of the Pearl?
让我来当船长吧
Name me captain.
我会在你的麾下效劳 抢来的东西上交一成
I'll sail under your colors. I'll give you 10% of me plunder.
而你就自封为舰队司令 巴博萨 撒维司令?
And you get to introduce yourself as Commodore Barbossa.
明白吗?
Savvy?
我看你是想让我别杀这个小崽子
I suppose in exchange, you want me not to kill the whelp.
不 不 不 根本不是这样 尽管杀他好了
No, no, no. Not at all. By all means, kill the whelp.
但不是现在
Just not yet.
等诅咒解除之后找个适当的机会
Wait to lift the curse until the opportune moment.
比如说
For instance...
在你消灭了诺灵顿的手下之后
After you've killed Norrington's men.
所有的敌人
Every last one.
你从开始就策划好了这一切
You've been planning this from the beginning.
自从你知道我的名字之后
Ever since you learned my name.
对啊
Yeah.
我要你劫掠收入的五成
I want 50% of your plunder.
- 一成五 - 四成
- 15%. - 40%.
二成五
25%.
我会给你买顶帽子
I'll buy you the hat.
真正的大帽子 准将大人
A really big one, Commodore.
我们说定了!
We have an accord.
所有人登船!
All hands to the boats!
不好意思
Apologies.
请你来下命令
You give the orders.
绅士们 出去走走!
Gents, take a walk.
不上小船?
Not to the boats?
别开枪!
Hold fire.
这就像希腊人进攻特洛伊一样
Oh, this is just like what the Greeks done at Troy.
只不过希腊人躲在马里 而不是化妆成女人
Except they was in a horse instead of dresses.
是木马
Wooden horse.
我进去一会儿
A moment, please.
伊丽莎白?
Elizabeth?
我只想让你知道
I just want you to know
你今天作了一个非常正确的决定
I believe you made a very good decision today.
我深深为你感到骄傲
Couldn't be more proud of you.
但你知道吗 即使是一个正确的决定
But, you know, even a good decision,
如果是源于错误的动机 那它也有可能变成一个错误的决定
if made for the wrong reasons, can be a wrong decision.
回去报告
Look into that. Report back.
上尉?
Lieutenant?
哟吼!
Yoo-hoo!
伊丽莎白?
Elizabeth?
你在吗?
Are you there?
伊丽莎白 你在听我说话吗?
Elizabeth, are you even listening to me?
哦 你干了什么啊? !
Oh, what have you done?
- 哦! - 不要这样!
- Oooh! - Stop that!
我感觉自己像个傻瓜
Already feel like a fool.
不过你看起来很迷人
Look nice, though.
是吗?
I look nice?
我必须承认 杰克 我本来自以为把你看透了
I must admit, Jack, I thought I had you figured.
可你仍然是一个难以捉摸的家伙
But it turns out you're a hard man to predict.
我? 我不算诚实
Me? I'm dishonest.
对我这样一个不守信的人 你应该习惯对我的忠诚不报太多希望
And a dishonest man you can always trust to be dishonest.
老实说
Honestly.
你尤其应该小心那些忠实的人
It's the honest ones you want to watch for,
因为你永远不清楚
because you can never predict
他们会做出些什么蠢事来
when they're going to do something incredibly stupid.
啊!
Aaah!
你的路走到尽头了 伙计
You're off the edge of the map, mate.
小心怪兽来了
Here there be monsters.
了解!
Right!
你想先吃那一部分呢?
What would you pick to eat first?
我想我们现在就可以决定
I think we should decide now.
这样等时候一到我们就不用忙了
Just so we're ready when the time comes.
那是什么?
What was that?
嘘!
Shh!
伊丽莎白!
Miss Elizabeth!
回船上去! 快!
Make for the ship! Move!
大船!
To the ship!
快划!
Row, men!
你别想打赢我 杰克!
You can't beat me, Jack.
真有趣
That's interesting.
魅力无穷啊 伙计
I couldn't resist, mate.
啊!
Aaah!
对不起!
Sorry!
现在怎么样 杰克 斯派洛?
So what now, Jack Sparrow?
两个不死的怪物就这么打下去
Are we to be two immortals locked in an epic battle
一直打到世界末日才能有个胜负之分
until judgment day and trumpets sound?
或者你可以考虑投降
Or you could surrender.
啊!
Aaaah!
大家都跟我来!
All of you with me!
威尔还在山洞里 我们得去救他
Will is in that cave. We must save him.
准备好了吗? 用力拉啊!
Ready. And heave!
拜托 我需要大家帮助 快点
Please, I need your help! Come on!
暴风雨中靠港停泊
Any port in a storm.
科顿没说错 我们已经搞到黑珍珠了
Cotton's right. We've got the Pearl,
那杰克怎么办 你们就这样丢下他?
What about Jack? Are you gonna leave him?
杰克欠我们一条船
Jack owes us a ship.
我们也有法典参详
There's the Code to consider.
法典?
The Code?
你们是海盗
You're pirates.
让法典和规矩都见鬼去吧!
Hang the Code, and hang the rules!
那些只不过是些指导而已
They're more like guidelines anyway.
该死的海盗!
Bloody pirates!
- 嘿! - 什么?
- Hey. - What?
这也是计划好的吗?
Is it supposed to be doing that?
他们在偷我们的船
They're stealing our ship!
该死的海盗!
Bloody pirates!
登船者 让开!
Boarders, away!
快!
Come on!
啊!
Gaaah!
我的眼睛!
Me eye!
我要让你知道什么才是痛苦
I'm gonna teach you the meaning of pain!
你喜欢痛苦吗?
Do you like pain?
那就去穿件女式胸衣试试
Try wearing a corset.
杰克站在哪一边?
Whose side is Jack on?
你是问现在?
At the moment?
不公平
No fair.
这支枪跟你有10年了 可惜你在浪费子弹而已
Ten years you carry that pistol, and now you waste your shot.
他没有浪费
He didn't waste it.
我感觉到...
I feel...
好冷
Cold.
停战行吗?
Parley?
这艘船是我们的了 先生们
The ship is ours, gentlemen.
胜利!
Huzzah!
我们应该返回无畏号
We should return to the Dauntless,
你的未婚夫一定急于知道你的安危
Your fiance will be wanting to know you're safe.
如果你还在等待一个好时机
If you were waiting for the opportune moment...
那就是刚才
That was it.
如果你能施恩
If you'd be so kind,
将我送到我的船上 我将感激不尽
I'd be much obliged if you'd drop me off at my ship.
我很抱歉 杰克
I'm sorry, Jack.
他们是按道上规矩做的 别指望更多
They done what's right by them. Can't expect more than that.
"杰克 斯派洛 著名的..."
"Jack Sparrow, be it known that you..."
船长 杰克 斯派洛船长
Captain. Captain Jack Sparrow.
“鉴于你对皇室政府所犯下的罪行
"For your willful commission of crimes against the crown.
罄竹难书
Said crimes being numerous in quantity
令人发指
and sinister in nature.
现列举重罪条目如下
The most egregious of these to be cited herewith.
海盗、走私...”
Piracy, smuggling..."
这样不对
This is wrong.
诺灵顿司令官必须依法办事
Commodore Norrington is bound by the law.
我们也是
As are we all.
假扮西班牙皇家海军军官
"lmpersonating an officer of the Spanish Royal Navy.
假扮英格兰教会神职人员
lmpersonating a cleric of the church of England."
呵
Ah, yeah.
伪装他国船只、纵火、绑架、劫掠、偷猎
"Sailing under false colors, arson, kidnapping,
盗窃、腐化堕落
looting, poaching, brigandage, pilfering, depravity,
破坏、藐视法律
depredation, and general lawlessness.
对于以上罪行的指控
And for these crimes
你今日被判绞刑
you have been sentenced to be, on this day,
立即处死
hung by the neck until dead.
愿上帝宽恕你的灵魂
May God have mercy on your soul."
斯旺市长
Governor Swann.
准将
Commodore.
伊丽莎白
Elizabeth.
我必须告诉你 自从我们相见的那一刻起
I should have told you every day from the moment I met you.
我就爱上了你
I love you.
士兵
Marines.
我喘不过气来了
I can't breathe.
伊丽莎白!
Elizabeth!
快!
Move!
什么...
What...
走开!
Move!
干嘛!
Come on!
- 好! - 来啊 年轻人!
- Right! - Come on, lads!
我早料到会有人劫法场
I thought we might endure some ill-conceived escape attempt.
不过没想到会是你
But not from you.
当年返回罗耶港途中 我救你一命
On our return to Port Royal, I granted you clemency.
而你就这样答谢我?
And this is how you thank me?
把你的大好前程都葬送在他身上?
By throwing in your lot with him?
他可是一个海盗!
He's a pirate!
也是一位好人
And a good man.
如果我所做的一切
If all I have achieved is the hangman
只是白搭上自己性命 那我也认了
will earn two pairs of boots instead of one, so be it.
我的良心告诉我这是对的
My conscience will be clear.
你忘记你的立场了 特纳
You forget your place, Turner.
在你和杰克之间我已作出了选择
It's right here between you and Jack.
还有我
As is mine.
伊丽莎白!
Elizabeth!
放下你们的武器!
Lower your weapons.
看在上帝份上放下枪!
For goodness sake, put them down!
那么这才是你的真心所在?
So this is where your heart truly lies, then?
是的
It is.
好吧 我不禁要为此拍手叫好
Well! I'm actually feeling rather good about this.
我想大家正处于一种微妙的关系
I think we've all arrived at a special place.
包括思维
Spiritually.
世界观
Ecumenically.
语言
Grammatically.
我想告诉你 我绝对支持你 伙计
I want you to know that I was rooting for you, mate.
知道吗
Know that.
伊丽莎白
Elizabeth.
但在我俩之间这些似乎都不起作用 亲爱的
It would never have worked between us, darling.
我很抱歉
I'm sorry.
威尔
Will.
帽子很漂亮
Nice hat.
各位!
Friends.
今天这个日子将会被各位永远记住
This is a day that you will always remember
因为这一天...
as the day that...
白痴 他除了绞架之外无处可去
ldiot. He has nowhere to go but back to the noose.
有船!
Sail ho!
下一步该怎么办?
What's your plan of action?
长官?
Sir?
也许在某些时候
Perhaps on the rare occasion
追寻正义之路需要海盗的存在
pursuing the right course demands an act of piracy,
海盗本身也是一种生存方式
piracy itself can be the right course?
特纳先生
Mr. Turner.
我会为我所做的一切承担责任
I will accept the consequences of my actions.
这柄剑很漂亮
This is a beautiful sword.
我希望打造它的人能够在自己的一生中
I would expect the man who made it to show the same care
展现更多的才华
in every aspect of his life.
谢谢你
Thank you.
准将!
Commodore!
斯派洛怎么办?
What about Sparrow?
我们不妨让他先得意些日子
Well, I think we can afford to give him one day's head start.
所以
So.
这就是你所选择的道路 是吗?
This is the path you've chosen, is it?
不管怎么说 他总算是个铁匠
After all, he is a blacksmith.
不
No.
他是个海盗
He's a pirate.
拉!
Heave!
我还以为你会按法典办事呢!
Thought you were supposed to keep to the Code.
我们只不过觉得那些条文更像是一种指导
We figured they were more actual guidelines.
谢谢你
Thank you.
斯派洛船长
Captain Sparrow.
黑珍珠号是你的了
The Black Pearl is yours.
大家各就各位!
On deck, you scabrous dogs!
转帆索准备!
Hands to braces!
现在...让我们驶向远方
Let down and haul to run free!
自由的一方
Now, bring me that horizon.
地地道道的大坏蛋
And really bad eggs.
让我们痛饮吧兄弟们!
Drink up, me hearties, yo ho!